ncdor.gov 2017-08-18

# NCDOR Privacy Policy

### **Privacy Statement**

Thank you for visiting the North Carolina Department of Revenue's (NCDOR) website. The purpose of this site is to provide information and educate users about the taxes we administer. This website also includes specific applications that provide services such as filing returns and paying taxes online, subscribing to receive electronic alerts about important tax issues, and various other services.

We will not collect personal information about you when you browse our website. The applications on this site that provide services such as (but not limited to) filing returns and paying tax online require that you provide certain personal and confidential information. Using these services is voluntary and providing the requested information implies your consent for us to use this data in order to respond to your specific request. Your personal information, including your e-mail address, will not be sold or shared with any other party except as permitted by law.

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy at any time without notice. 

### Information Collected

When you visit our website, we automatically collect and store the following information: 

  1. The name of the domain; for example, "123company.com";
  2. An IP (Internet Protocol) address, which is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you are using the Internet;
  3. The type of browser and operating system you use to access the NCDOR site;
  4. The web pages you visit within the site and any form, publication or document that you download;
  5. The date and time you visit the site;
  6. The links made to other web sites through the NCDOR site. 

We use this information to learn about the number of visitors to the site, the items of most and least interest to visitors, and system performance or problems in an effort to continually improve the site’s usefulness to the public.

### International ACH Transaction (IAT) Rules

It is the intent of the North Carolina Department of Revenue not to use the ACH system for transactions in violation of US Law, including the sanctions administered by the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). It is also the intent of the agency to be in compliance with the "International ACH Transaction (IAT) rules" that are part of the NACHA Operating Rules. Accordingly, all ACH payments made through this website are intended only for payments not associated with a foreign bank account, which would classify it as an "International ACH Transaction (IAT)" under the NACHA Operating Rules. Since this website's payment applications do not accommodate IAT transactions, payors that would be considered an IAT payor should use alternative payment methods for remitting funds to the agency.

### E-mail

E-mail is not a secure means of communication. Therefore, you should _never_ send confidential information (e.g. Social Security numbers, tax account numbers) through e-mail. To protect your privacy, we will not send sensitive or confidential information to anyone in an e-mail unless the sensitive or confidential information is in an encrypted attachment. Also we will not use e-mail to request personal, tax or financial information. 

### Security

Physical, electronic and procedural safeguards are in place to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to preserve data integrity, and to ensure the appropriate use of confidential information you provide on our website. We use industry-standard encryption technology when collecting or transferring confidential information. 

For general website security purposes and to ensure that our site remains available to all users, we employ software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Use of our site constitutes consent to such monitoring. Unauthorized attempts to upload information and/or change information on this website are strictly prohibited and are subject to legal action.

### Cookies

A "persistent" cookie is generally defined as a piece of data that is stored on the user's hard drive. We do not use "persistent" cookies on our website or in our web applications. ****

"Temporary" or "session" cookies are used on all NCDOR website pages. These cookies are stored in memory and are only available during an active browser session.  Session cookies are also used by some of the applications deployed on our website to temporarily save information entered by a user as long as the user's browser is open. These cookies do not collect personal information on users, and they are erased as soon as you close your web browser.  No personally identifiable information about you is maintained as a result of a temporary or session cookie. 

You can configure your web browser to accept or decline cookies, or to alert you when cookies are in use. You do not have to accept cookies from us, but if you choose not to, some of the functions on our site may not be available to you.

### Links or References to Other Sites

You should be aware that other websites that you link to from our site may contain privacy provisions that differ from the provisions of our Privacy Policy. 

References or links on the North Carolina Department of Revenue’s website to any other website, process, or service, is for the information and convenience of our taxpayers, and does not constitute endorsement or recommendation by the North Carolina Department of Revenue.

### Information About Online Tracking 

Some browsers incorporate a "Do Not Track" feature that signals to websites you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. Tracking is not the same as using or collecting information in connection with a single website. For these purposes, tracking refers to collecting personally identifiable information from consumers who use or visit a website or online service as they move across different websites over time. 

How browsers communicate the "Do Not Track" signal is not yet uniform. As a result, our Website is not yet set up to interpret or respond to "Do Not Track" signals communicated by your browser. Even so, as described more fully within our Privacy Policy, we limit our collection and use of your personal information. 

For a description of "Do Not Track" protocols for browsers and mobile devices, or to simply learn more about the choices available to you, you can visit the All About Do Not Track website: [http://allaboutdnt.com](http://allaboutdnt.com/).
